Guide to the Salo W. Baron Papers, 1900-1980
Department of Special Collections
- Series 7. Pamphlets, Reprints and Books Series, 27.5 linear ft. (55 boxes)
  - Subseries 2. Article Reprints
    - Subsubseries 2. By Subject
      - U.S. Jews, Dutch Jews, South African Jews. The Progressive Jew 3:2, August/September 1946 (Johannesburg: South African Union for Progressive Judaism).August/September 1946 (Box 623)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. Academic Committee on Soviet Jewry, Soviet Jewry, 1969.1969 (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. Amercian Jewish Conference on Soviet Jewry. Informational materials, 1969.1969 (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. Columbia University, Russian-language booklet on Archive of Russian and Eastern European history and culture [n.d].n.d. (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. Moshe Decter, ed., A Hero for Our Time. The Trial and Fate of Boris Kochubiyevsky (Conference on Status of Soviet Jews and Academic Committee on Soviet Jewry: New York, 1970).1970 (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. Moshe Decter, ed., Redemption! Jewish Freedom Letters from Russia (Conference on Status of Soviet Jews and Academic Committee on Soviet Jewry: New York, 1970).1970 (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. Abraham Duker, "The Catholic Centrists and the Jewish Probelm in the Polish `Great Emigration,'" Jubilee Volume N.M. Gelber (Tel Aviv, 1963), v-xii.1963 (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. Abraham Duker, "Hollaenderski's Letter of Inquiry to Lelewel," Studies in Bibliography and Booklore 1:4 (December 1954), 161-166.December 1954 (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. Abraham Duker, "Jewish Participants in the Polish Insurrection of 1863," in Meir Ben-horin et al., eds., Studies and Essays in Honor of Abraham A. Neuman (Leiden, 1962), 144-153.1962 (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. Abraham Duker, "Jewish Participants in the Polish November (1830-31) Insurrection," in The Abraham Weiss Jubilee Volume (New York, 1964), 81-87. 1964 (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. Abraham Duker, "Jewish Volunteers in the Ottoman-Polish Cossack Units During the Crimean War," Jewish Social Studies 16:3 and 4, 203-218, 351-376. (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. Abraham Duker, "The Lafayette Committee for Jewish Emancipation," Essays on Jewish Life and Thought (New York, 1959, 169-182.1959 (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. Abraham Duker, "The Polish Democratic Society and the Jewish Problem, 1932-46," Jewish Social Studies 19:3-4 (July-October 1957), 99-112.July-October 1957 (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. Abraham Duker, "Prince Czartoryski, the Emigre, on the Jewish Problem," in Abraham Berger et al., eds, The Joshua Bloch Memorial Volume (New York, 1960), 165-179.1960 (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. Abraham Duker, "The Situation of the Jews in Poland," reprinted by courtesy of the Conference on Jewish Relations (American Jewish Congress: New York, April 1936). April 1936 (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. Abraham Duker, "Some Aspects of Polish-Jewish Relations in the United States after 1865," The Jewish Quarterly Review 45 (April 1955), 529-539.April 1955 (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. Abraham Duker, "Wladyslaw Dzwonkowski, an `Enlightened' Towianist, on the Jewish Problem, 1862," Meyer Waxman Jubilee Volume (Jerusalem and Tel-Aviv, 1966), 57-75.1966 (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. Israel Getzler, "The Mensheviks," Problems of Communism, November-December 1967, 15-29.1967 (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. Solomon I. Goldelman, Jewish National Autotnomy in Ukraine, 1917-1920 (Chicago, 1968).1968 (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. Informationsbulletin (December 1959). Rat der jüdischen Gemeinden in Böhmen und Mähren zu Prag.December 1959 (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. Jewish Life in Poland, no. 12 (July 1950) and no. 16 (July 1951) (Polish Research and Information Service, New York).July 1951 (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. The Kishinev Massachre. Proceedings of a Meeting of Citizens of New York, Carnegie Hall, May 27, 1903 (New York, 1903).May 27, 1903 (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. William Korey, Jews as Non-Persons: A Study of Soviet History Textbooks in Elementary and Secondary Schools (B'nai B'rith: Washington, D.C., n.d.). (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. M.I. Lazerson, Russian-language booklet on the Jewish question (Petrograd, 1917).1917 (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. Isasc Lewin, "The Protection of Jewish Religious Rights by Royal Edicts in Ancient Poland," Quarterly Bulltetin of the Polish Institute of Arts and Science in America (April 1943), 3-23.April 1943 (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. Isasc Lewin, "The Protection of Jewish Religious Rights by Royal Edicts in Ancient Poland," Quarterly Bulltetin of the Polish Institute of Arts and Science in America (April 1943), 3-23.April 1943 (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. Light on Soviet Jewry. Report of a Conference on Jews in the USSR. (Board of Deputies of British Jews: London, June 1969).June 1969 (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. J. Rülf, Die russischen Juden. Ihre Leidensgeschichte und unsere Rettungsversuche (Memel, 1892).1892 (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. J. Rülf, Die russischen Juden. Ihre Leidensgeschichte und unsere Rettungsversuche (Memel, 1892).1892 (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. Rumanian Jewry in the Postwar Period (Institute of Jewish Affairs: New York, 1952).1952 (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. The Soviet Involvement in the Middle East. An American Press Commentary [no publisher, no date]. (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. Leon Szczekacz, Ghetto Koltubanka (History of the Project to Organize a Jewish Legion with the Polish Army in the USSR) (Paris, Tel-Aviv, New York, 1951).1951 (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. Veridicus, Les Infractions au Traite des Minorites en Roumanie (Budapest, 1925).1925 (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. Misc. (Box 624)
      - Eastern Europe and USSR. Hebrew pamphlets. (Box 624)
      - Middle East and Islam. Asia (May, 1942).May, 1942 (Box 625)
      - Middle East and Islam. Isaac Bloch, Les Israelites d'Oran de 1792 a 1815 (Paris, 1886).1886 (Box 625)
      - Middle East and Islam. M. Chanis, The Wrong Arabs (New York, 1948).1948 (Box 625)
      - Middle East and Islam. Albert Einstein and Eric Kahler, The Arabs and Palestine (reprinted from the Princeton Herald, 1944). (Box 625)
      - Middle East and Islam. Suraiya Farouqhi (1971).1971 (Box 625)
      - Middle East and Islam. W.J. Fischel (1963).1963 (Box 625)
      - Middle East and Islam. H.A.R. Gibb, The Arabs. Oxford Pamphlets of World Affairs, nol 36 (Oxford, 1941).1941 (Box 625)
      - Middle East and Islam. D. Jacoby (n.d.).n.d. (Box 625)
      - Middle East and Islam. Jewish Quarterly Review (1964-65).1964-65 (Box 625)
      - Middle East and Islam. Majid Khadduri (1953).1953 (Box 625)
      - Middle East and Islam. I.J. Kligler and Ziporah Friedmann-Makoff, The Yemenite Refugee Camp in Aden (American Jewish Joint Distribution Committee: Jerusalem, 1944). (Box 625)
      - Middle East and Islam. Theodor Kluge, "Die Lykier," in Der Alte Orient 2:2, 1910 (Leipzig).1910 (Box 625)
      - Middle East and Islam. Herbert Liebesny (1953).1953 (Box 625)
      - Middle East and Islam. Robert Mantran (1962).1962 (Box 625)
      - Middle East and Islam. The Near East (Feb. 1954).Feb. 1954 (Box 625)
      - Middle East and Islam. Bezalel Porten (1961).1961 (Box 625)
      - Middle East and Islam. Bernard Rosenblatt, Federated Palestine and the Jewish Commonwealth (Scopus: New York, 1941).1941 (Box 625)
      - Middle East and Islam. Gerard Salinger (1950).1950 (Box 625)
      - Middle East and Islam. Turkish tourism brochures (1950s).1950s (Box 625)
      - Middle East and Islam. Herbert H. Williams (1953-53).1953-53 (Box 625)
      - General Law. Milton R. Konvitz (1937).1937 (Box 626)
      - General Law. Basic Law for the Federal Republic of Germany (1949).1949 (Box 626)
      - General Law. Edmond N. Cahn (1951).1951 (Box 626)
      - General Law. Morris R. Cohen (1937).1937 (Box 626)
      - General Law. Arno Carl Coutinho (1938).1938 (Box 626)
      - General Law. Maurice Finkelstein (1952).1952 (Box 626)
      - General Law. Isaac Husik (1938).1938 (Box 626)
      - General Law. Grayson Kirk (1952).1952 (Box 626)
      - General Law. Harold D. Lasswell (n.d.).n.d. (Box 626)
      - General Law. Lena London (1948).1948 (Box 626)
      - General Law. Cecilia Hz. de Mendoza, Miguel Antonio Caro. Diversos Aspects de um humanista colombiano (Bogota, 1943).1943 (Box 626)
      - General Law. Franz Neumann (1949).1949 (Box 626)
      - General Law. Leo Pfeffer (1951).1951 (Box 626)
      - General Law. Charles Recht, The Right of Asylum (The Social Economic Foundation, Inc.: New York, n.d.).n.d. (Box 626)
      - General Law. Frank Schechter (1933, 1935).1933, 1935 (Box 626)
      - General Law. I.L. Sharfman (1946).1946 (Box 626)
      - General Law. Helen Silving (1942).1942 (Box 626)
      - Conference Proceedings. Provincial Jewry in Victorian Britain. Conference Papers, Jewish Historical Society of England (London, July 1975).July 1975 (Box 627)
      - Conference Proceedings. Proceedings of the International Conference on Historical Population Studies. Sponsored by Daedalus and the Harvard Center for Population Studies. Vol. I. (Boston, October 1966).October 1966 (Box 627)
      - Conference Proceedings. Proceedings of the International Conference on Historical Population Studies. Sponsored by Daedalus and the Harvard Center for Population Studies. Vol. II. (Boston, October 1966).October 1966 (Box 627)
      - The American Jew, 1654-1954. A brief reading list... Public Library of Cincinnati and Hamilton County, 1954-55.1954-55 (Box 628)
      - Archives in Israel (Jerusalem, 1959).1959 (Box 628)
      - Archives juives 2:4 and 3:1 (Paris, 1965-67).1965-67 (Box 628)
      - Joshua Bloch, "Early Hebrew Printing in Spain and Portugal." Reprinted from the Bulletin of the New York Public Library, May 1938. May 1938 (Box 628)
      - Joshua Bloch, Nazi-Germany and the Jews. An Annotated Bibliography (The American Jewish Committee: New York, 1936).1936 (Box 628)
      - Bernhard Blumenkranz, Bibliographie des Juifs en France (Paris, 1961).1961 (Box 628)
      - Commission on European Jewish Cultural Reconstruction, Tentative List of Jewish Periodicals in Axis-Occuppied Countries. Supplement to Jewish Social Studies 9:3, 1947.1947 (Box 628)
      - Commission on European Jewish Cultural Reconstruction, Tentative List of Jewish Periodicals in Axis-Occuppied Countries. Supplement to Jewish Social Studies 9:3, 1947.1947 (Box 628)
      - Abraham G. Duker, A Basic Bibliography of Books in Jewish Background for the Communal Worker (Training Bureau for Jewish Communal Service: New York, 1947).1947 (Box 628)
      - Moses Einhorn, "Three Decades," Hebrew Medical Journal vol. II, 1957 (American edition) and vols. I and II, 1957 (Israel edition).1957 (Box 628)
      - Ladislas Farago, ed., German Psychological Warfare. Survey and Bibliography (Committee for National Morale: New York, 1941). 1941 (Box 628)
      - Michael Freund, Bibliography on Community Organization (Training Bureau for Jewish Communal Service: New York, 1948) ("experimental edition").1948 (Box 628)
      - Louis Ginzberg, "Isaac Hirsch Weiss," (no publication or date) 1-11. (Box 628)
      - Tobey B. Gitelle, "Preliminary List and Subject Index of Jewish Social Studies, 1964 through 1978," Jewish Social Studies 41:1 (Winter 1979).Winter 1979 (Box 628)
      - Norman Golb, "The Topography of the Jews of Medieval Egypt," Journal of Near Eastern Studies 24:3 (July 1965), 251-270.July 1965 (Box 628)
      - Dr. Max Golde. Ein Erinnerungsblatt zu seinem 60. Geburtstag (Berlin, 1928).1928 (Box 628)
      - Herbert F. Hahn, Religions of the Ancient Near East (to 323 B.C.). A Bibliography, 1920-1939. [typescript]1920-1939 (Box 628)
      - Ephim H. Jeshurin, R.J. Bialostotzky. Bibliography (New York, 1958).1958 (Box 628)
      - Ephim H. Jeshurin, S. Niger. Bibliography (1958).1958 (Box 628)
      - Ephim H. Jeshurin, Harry Rogoff. Bibliography (New York, 1958).1958 (Box 628)
      - Kirjath Sepher. Bibliographical Quarterly of the Jewish National and University Library, Jerusalem. Vols. 19-22, April 1942-January/April 1946.April 1942-January/April 1946 (Box 629)
      - Elmer N. Lear, Bibliography of Recent Periodical Literature pertaining to the American-Jewish Community (B'nai B'rith Department of Adult Education: Washington, D.C. [no date]). (Box 629)
      - E. Lifschutz, Bibliography of American and Canadian Jewish Memoirs and Autobiographies (YIVO: New York, 1970).1970 (Box 629)
      - Rudolf Loewenthal, ed., "The Judeo-Muslim Marranos of Bukhara. Two Russian Articles," Central Asian Collectanea, No. 1 (Washington, D. C., 1958).1958 (Box 629)
      - Isidore S. Meyer (1949).1949 (Box 629)
      - Helen Huss Pankhurst, Great Books. Recommended Readings... (Barnard College, Columbia University, 1943).1943 (Box 629)
      - Leona Rostenberg, "The Printing of Hebrew Text Books in Strasburg, 1544-1549," Journal of Jewish Bibliography 2:2-3 (April-July 1940), 1-5.April-July 1940 (Box 629)
      - J. Schäffer, Albert Neisser. Lebenswerk. Persönlichkeit. Erinnerungen aus seinem Leben (Berlin and Vienna, 1917).1917 (Box 629)
      - Hermann Schreiber, Schrimmer Jugenderinnerungen (Berlin, 1927).1927 (Box 629)
      - Sigmund Seeligmann, Bibliographie en historie. Bijdrage tot de geschiedenis der eerste Sephardim in Amsterdam (Amsterdam, 1927).1927 (Box 629)
      - Shlomo Shunami, "Bibliographies of Jewish Authors Published in the years 5699-5707 (1939-1947)," Semitic Studies in Memory of Immanuel Low (Budapest, 1947).1939-1947 (Box 629)
      - Shlomo Shunami, The Writings of Izhak Ben-Zvi. A Bibliography, 1904-1958 (Jerusalem, 1958).1958 (Box 629)
      - 1 Hebrew-language bibliography. (Box 629)
    - Subsubseries 4. Pop culture
      - The Ballet Theatre. Program, 1956.1956 (Box 630)
      - Carnegie Hall. 6 programs, 1955/56.1955/56 (Box 630)
      - Finian's Rainbow. Program, 1955.1955 (Box 630)
      - Football programs, 1951.1951 (Box 630)
      - Hagadah, Maxwell House Coffee, 1951.1951 (Box 630)
      - Jester of Columbia 51:4. (Box 630)
      - Wright Patman, Our American Government (Chicago, 1948).1948 (Box 630)
      - The Pedagogic Reporter 3:1 (September 1951), published by the American Association for Jewish Education.1951 (Box 630)
      - Picturegoer, February 17, 1951.February 17, 1951 (Box 630)
      - Playbills. (Box 630)
      - Roxy Theatre. (Box 630)
      - The Tales of Hoffmann. Program. (Box 630)
      - United Nations information, 1949-50.1949-50 (Box 630)
  - Subseries 3. Catalogs
    - Subsubseries 1. Library and museum catalogs
      - Antiquariatskatalog, Berichte Nr. 6, Silesiaca. 1926. Buchhandlung Preuss & Jünger, Breslau.1926 (Box 631)
      - Aus Breslauer öffentlichen Bibliotheken und Archiven. Katalog der Ausstellung im Kunstgewerbemuseum (Breslau, 1926).1926 (Box 631)
      - Bibliothek der israelitischen Cultusgemeinde Zürich. Katalog, 1. Nachtrag (August 1947 bis Dezember 1948) (Zurich, 1949).1949 (Box 631)
      - Bücherverzeichnis der Bibliothek des Vereins für jüdische Geschichte und Literatur zu Ratibor (Beuthen O.S., n.d.).n.d. (Box 631)
      - Bücherverzeichnis der israelitischen Bibliothek Ratibor (1894).1894 (Box 631)
      - The Central Zionist Archives (Jerusalem, ca. 1956). English and Hebrew versions of archive guide.1956 (Box 631)
      - Hebrew Union College-Jewish Institute of Religion, Some Recent Acquisitions of Books Dated 1953-1955 (December 1955).December 1955 (Box 631)
      - Hebrew Union College-Jewish Institute of Religion, Some Recent Acquisitions (1962).1962 (Box 631)
      - Institute of Jewish Studies, Manchester. Second Bi-Annual Report, Sessions 1956-1957.1956-1957 (Box 631)
      - M. & H. Marcus, publishers in Breslau. Catalog, 1936.1936 (Box 631)
      - Menasseh ben Israel, 1604-1657. Catalogus van de Tentoonstelling... (Joods Historisch Museum: Amsterdam, 1957).1957 (Box 631)
      - J. Partsch, ed., Literatur der Landes- und Volkskunde der Provinz Schlesien, nos. 4-6. Supplementary numbers for the 74th to 76th Jahresbericht der schlesischen Gesellschaft für vaterländischen Cultur [sic] (Breslau, 1896-98).1896-98 (Box 631)
      - Staats- und Universitätsbibliothek Breslau, Jahresbericht 1932 (Breslau, 1933).1933 (Box 631)
      - Stadtbibliothek Breslau. Wissensnötiges und Wissenswertes für den Besucher (Breslau, 1933) [2 copies].1933 (Box 631)
      - Yad La-Kore (The Reader's Aid) 1:1-2 (May-June 1946). Tel-Aviv.May-June 1946 (Box 631)
      - 9 Hebrew-language pamphlets and books. (Box 631)
    - Subsubseries 2. Booksellers Catalogs
      - E.J. Brill (Box 632)
      - Bamberger & Wahrmann (Box 632)
      - Bibliographischer Monatsbericht (listing of German university publications) (Leipzig, 1930, 1939, 1940). (Box 632)
      - M. Bernstein (Box 632)
      - Bloch (Box 632)
      - Bronfman Collection of Jewish Canadiana (Box 632)
      - Bronfman Collection of Jewish Canadiana (Box 632)
      - Consejo Superior de Investigaciones Cientificas (Madrid) (Box 632)
      - Christie's (Box 632)
      - Lucien Dorbon (Box 632)
      - East and West Shop (Box 632)
      - J.H. Flint (Box 633)
      - David Frankel (Box 633)
      - A. Golub (Box 633)
      - A. Golub (Box 633)
      - Paul Guenther (Box 633)
      - Otzar Haseforim (Box 633)
      - Israel Information Services (Box 633)
      - Fred Host (Box 633)
      - Kedem (Berlin) (Box 633)
      - KTAV (Box 633)
      - Heinz Lafaire (Box 633)
      - J.C.B. Mohr (Box 633)
      - Ge Nabrink (Box 633)
      - Nijhoff (Box 633)
      - Georg Olms (Box 634)
      - A. Packter (Box 634)
      - Parke-Bennett Galleries (Box 634)
      - Philo Press (Box 634)
      - Leona Rostenberg (Box 634)
      - Sänger & Friedberg (Frankfurt) (Box 634)
      - P. Schippers (Box 634)
      - P. Schippers (Box 634)
      - P. Schippers (Box 634)
      - P. Schippers (Box 634)
      - Stechert-Hafner (Box 634)
      - Zionist Literature (Box 634)
      - Bottega d'Erasmo (Box 635)
      - de Graaf (Box 635)
      - Rubin Mass (Box 635)
      - Zionist Literature (Box 635)
      - Zionist Literature (Box 635)
      - Zionist Literature (Box 635)
      - Zohar (Box 635)
      - Misc. (Box 635)
      - Misc. (Box 635)
      - Misc. (Box 635)
      - Misc. (Box 635)
      - Misc. Book & Periodical Advertisements (Box 635)
  - Subseries 4. Periodical runs
    - Detroit Jewish Chronicle (1946-47)1946-47 (Box 636)
    - Detroit Jewish Chronicle (1946-47)1946-47 (Box 637)
    - Near East Report (1966-71). Washington, D.C.1966-71 (Box 638)
    - Hebrew periodicals. (Box 638)
  - Subseries 5. Manuscripts
    - Arabic-script manuscript [might be printed]. Bound. No identifying marks in Roman alphabet. Ca. 200 pp. (Box 639)
    - Manuscript, "Ad Pium Lectorum Instructio et Praefatio Admonitoria." Illustrated. No date. 231 pp. (Box 639)
    - Manuscript cookbook. May be in Spanish. No date. 48 pp. (Box 639)
    - Manuscript, "Riposta al libro che fu dato alle stampe dal [unclear] intitolato la sinagoga disingannata," 1702. (Box 639)
    - Manuscript, "Regolamento interno della comunita israelita di Ferrara per gli anni 1829, 30, 31." (Box 639)
    - German letter from A. Berliner, 1905.1905 (Box 639)
    - 1-page Italian manuscript, no date.no date (Box 639)
    - Hebrew manuscripts and fragments. (Box 639)
  - Subseries 6. Books
    - Subsubseries 1. By Baron
      - Salo Wittmayer Baron. Jubilee Volume. English Section, Vol. I (American Academy for Jewish Research: Jerusalem, 1974). (Box 640)
      - Salo Wittmayer Baron. Jubilee Volume. English Section, Vol. II (American Academy for Jewish Research: Jerusalem, 1974). (Box 640)
      - Hebrew-language version of above. (Box 640)
      - Salo Baron, History and Jewish Historians (Philadelphia, 1964).1964 (Box 641)
      - Salo Baron, The Jewish Community. Its History and Structure to the American Revolution. Vol. I (Westport, Connecticut, 1942). (Box 641)
      - Salo Baron, The Russian Jew under Tsars and Soviets (New York, 1964).1964 (Box 641)
      - Salo Baron, Steeled by Adversity (Philadelphia, 1971).1971 (Box 641)
      - Salo Baron, Die Judenfrage auf dem Wiener Kongress (Vienna and Berlin, 1920).1920 (Box 642)
      - Salo Baron, Modern Nationalism and Religion (New York, 1960).1960 (Box 642)
      - Salo Baron, A Social and Religious History of the Jews. Volume 1 of 3 (New York, 1937).1937 (Box 642)
        Subseries 6. Books
      - Salo Baron, A Social and Religious History of the Jews. Volume XVI: Late Middle Ages and Era of European Expansion (1200-1650); Poland-Lithuania 1500-1650 (New York, 1976, 2nd ed.). (Box 642)
      - Salo Wittmayer Baron. Jubilee Volume. Vols. 1-3 (Jerusalem, 1974).1974 (Box 643)
    - Subsubseries 2. Nazi Books
      - Richard Benzing, Grundlagen der körperlichen und geistigen Erziehung des Kleinkindes im nationalsozialistischen Kindergarten (Berlin, 1941). (Box 644)
      - Dich ruft die SS (Berlin and Leipzig, n.d.).n.d. (Box 644)
      - Hans Draeger, Der Vertag von Versailles (Berlin, 1933).1933 (Box 644)
      - Ellenbeck, Der Offizier als Führer im Kampf gegen die feindliche Propaganda. (no publication information given)(Jan. 1943). (Box 644)
        Subsubseries 2. Nazi Books
      - Else Frobenius, Die Frau im Dritten Reich (Berlin, n.d.).n.d. (Box 644)
      - Des Führers Kampf um den Weltfrieden (Munich, 1936).1936 (Box 644)
      - Frederick to Gaste, Die Wahrheit über die jüdischen Ritualmorde (Berlin, n.d.).n.d. (Box 644)
      - Paul Haller, Die Lösung der Judenfrage in Deutschland (Berlin, 1939).1939 (Box 644)
      - Die Infanterie. Waffenhefte des Heeres (Munich, n.d.).n.d. (Box 644)
      - Das junge Deutschland. Amtliches Organ des Jugendführers des Deutschen Reiches 37:8, 1943 (Berlin).1943 (Box 644)
      - Nationalpolitische Aufklärungsschriften (series): No. 1: Heinz Oskar Schaefer, Grundzüge der nationalsozialistischen Weltanschauung (Berlin, 1935).1935 (Box 644)
      - Nationalpolitische Aufklärungsschriften (series): No. 2: R. Ströbel, Unseres Volkes Ursprung (Berlin, 1936).1936 (Box 644)
      - Nationalpolitische Aufklärungsschriften (series): No.3: Walter Gruber, Der Schicksalsweg des deutschen Volkes bis zum Weltkrieg (Berlin, 1936).1936 (Box 644)
      - Nationalpolitische Aufklärungsschriften (series): No. 4: Heinz Oskar Schaefer, Abriss der Geschichte der Bewegung (Berlin, 1935).1935 (Box 644)
      - Nationalpolitische Aufklärungsschriften (series): No. 5: Rudolf Frercks, Das rassische Erwachen des deutschen Volkes (Berlin, 1935).1935 (Box 644)
      - Nationalpolitische Aufklärungsschriften (series): No.6: Hans Wilhelm Scheidt, Der Arbeitsdienst: eine Willensäusserung der deutschen Jugend (Berlin, 1935)., 1935 (Box 644)
      - Nationalpolitische Aufklärungsschriften (series): No. 7: Eberhard Hautter, Das Sozialproblem im Wandel deutscher Geschichte (Berlin, 1937).1937 (Box 644)
      - Nationalpolitische Aufklärungsschriften (series): No. 8: Heinz Oskar Schaefer, Bolschewismus. Von der liberalistisch-marxistischen Weltanschauung zur Politik der Volkszerstörung (Berlin, 1937). (Box 644)
      - Nationalpolitische Aufklärungsschriften (series): No. 9: J. Appel, Deutsche Kolonien. Die Forderung des dritten Reiches (Berlin, n.d.). n.d. (Box 644)
      - Nationalpolitische Aufklärungsschriften (series): No. 10: Wilhelm Staudinger, Die Landwritschaft im deutschen Aufbauwerk (Berlin, 1937).1937 (Box 644)